<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre on Refresh Annapolis Valley</title>
    <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organizations/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre on Refresh Annapolis Valley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <atom:link href="https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organizations/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Entrepreneurship: Turning Ideas into Action</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/creative-entrepreneurship-turning-ideas-into-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 12:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/creative-entrepreneurship-turning-ideas-into-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Problems and solutions.  In between are the numerous ideas that eventually lead to innovative solutions and new business opportunities.  Join the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre&#34;&gt;
    
        Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre
    
&lt;/a&gt;
 for a talk all about ideas.  Where do they come from?  How do we nurture them?  How can we turn them into problem solving new business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build your mad ideation skills at this workshop, then take them to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.startituplaunchbox.com/&#34;&gt;Start It Up&lt;/a&gt;: our business ideation competition with $10K in prizes on the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pizza + workshop + building&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring your own laptop. A small number of laptops will be available to borrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First time Hoisters need to get a parent or guardian to &lt;a href=&#34;https://form.jotform.ca/71164477795267&#34;&gt;fill out the consent form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth Garrett</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/elizabeth-garrett/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/elizabeth-garrett/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just like becoming an expert in wine - you learn by drinking it, the best you can afford - you learn great food by finding the best there is, whether simply or luxurious. Then you savor it, analyze it, discuss it with your companions, and you compare it with other experiences&amp;rdquo; - Julia Child, &lt;em&gt;Mastering the Art of French Cooking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redefining Work: Coworking</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/redefining-work-coworking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 19:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/redefining-work-coworking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is lots of buzz around coworking spaces as a new way for independent and SME creative professionals to engage work. Coworking is about shared office space for professionals, but it is also about a style of work that suggests there are greater opportunities working in a diverse community setting. Coworking spaces themself are diverse in structure, ranging from the community powered, real-estate centric, to highbred business incubators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In rural Nova Scotia, numerous coworking spaces are springing up. The HUB South Shore in Mahone Bay, L-Ink&amp;rsquo;d in Annapolis Royal, CO3 in Bridgewater, The Hub Yarmouth, The Hub Annapolis Valley, the Rural Innovation Centre at Acadia University. Wow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a virtual tour of these coworking spaces. Learn about their unique take on coworking, and how they envision redefining how we do work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>