<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organizations on Refresh Annapolis Valley</title>
    <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organizations on Refresh Annapolis Valley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia Computer Science Society</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-computer-science-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-computer-science-society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Acadia Computer Science Society welcomes not only Computer Science students but all students enrolled at Acadia University. We endeavour to be an advocate for students with interests in computer science and technology. We plan events like banquets, CaCHe, LAN parties, and seminars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;AEC has been developing and delivering workshops for business professionals, entrepreneurs, and not-for-profits for over 25 years. AEC continues to innovate and develop new and relevant programs for today’s business professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rural-innovation-centre&#34;&gt;Rural Innovation Centre&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rural Innovation Centre (RIC) supports entrepreneurs and businesses in the Annapolis Valley and on the South Shore by providing training, advisory and consulting services to small businesses, government and not-for-profit organizations. The Rural Innovation Centre is an incubator for start up companies to access working space and support, networking events, mentors and connect to Acadia faculty and facilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;launchbox&#34;&gt;Launchbox&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/launchbox&#34;&gt;
    
        Launchbox
    
&lt;/a&gt;
 is the centre for student entrepreneurs, located on the 4th floor of Patterson Hall at Acadia University. We support students in their entrepreneurial pursuits by providing free programming, networking, access to mentors, and other entrepreneurs, working space and competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia Institute for Data Analytics</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-institute-for-data-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-institute-for-data-analytics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Rural Canada feeds our nation literally, economically, and environmentally.  It provides the food, fiber, minerals, water and other bio-resources and natural resources on which our country depends and the arteries of transportation by which they are delivered.  Digital technologies and data analytics can help us shape how we work with these resources and their impact on our local communities and our planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;mission&#34;&gt;Mission&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To advance knowledge in data analytics through collaborative and interdisciplinary research, education and outreach and to foster the ethical application and commercialization of data analytic solutions to challenges facing industry, government and society in rural Canada. The institute will initially focus on agriculture, food production, the environment, and green energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goals-and-objectives&#34;&gt;Goals and Objectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goals of the Acadia Institute for Data Analytics are to foster collaboration and the sharing of data analytics methods, technologies, and ethical practices among its stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, the Institute will gather active stakeholders as members (academic researchers, teachers, associations, companies, government departments, etc.); foster communications and collaboration among members; communicate and coordinate relevant meetings and other events; and make connections with other data analytics organizations.  The Institute will share knowledge of technologies and methods and promote the ethical use of data analytics methods that protect the privacy of individuals and the security and integrity of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objectives of the Acadia Institute for Data Analytics can be divided into four categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promotion and Outreach: To provide visibility for data analytics initiatives undertaken by members and communicate relevant events to industry, government and the public.  To make the institute relevant to rural business and industry.  To foster sharing of knowledge and use of data analytics through vehicles such as web inventories of member competencies and resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research:  To encourage, facilitate and leverage fundamental and interdisciplinary research and to attract high quality visiting scholars.  To work with members to provide shared technical infrastructure for research and development where possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education: To facilitate the development and delivery of educational programs such as short courses, training workshops, and seminars that are focused on the needs of members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application and Commercialization: To foster the development of innovative applications for use in academia, industry and government.  To establish Nova Scotia as a leader in the application of data analytics to rural problems. To stimulate technology transfer, commercialization and the development of new startups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia Robotics Program</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-robotics-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-robotics-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Robot Programming Competition mission is to increase interest in building digital technology and computer science by engaging Nova Scotia students in annual robotics programming competitions and related activities that feature problem solving and teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Acadia Robotics Program, through the Jodrey School of Computer Science, depends heavily on financial support from external organizations and the committed volunteers who annually contribute to the season from late August through to mid-June.  We have a junior program, FIRST® LEGO® League, and a senior program, Robofest. All the outreach throughout the season culminates in a Provincial Robot Programming Championship here at Acadia Unversity each February, involving over 400 participants, 100 volunteers, media and many organizations.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/qA3L8_KJB4c&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia School of Business</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-school-of-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-school-of-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acadia BBA students majoring in Entrepreneurship and Innovation are given the tools needed to succeed as entrepreneurs as well as to manage entrepreneurship for continuous innovation, sustainable competitive advantage and growth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia University</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-university/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Far above the dykes of Fundy&lt;br&gt;
And its basin blue&lt;br&gt;
Stands our noble alma mater&lt;br&gt;
Glorious to view&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lift the chorus&lt;br&gt;
Speed it onward&lt;br&gt;
Sing it loud and free&lt;br&gt;
Hail to thee our alma mater&lt;br&gt;
Acadia, hail to thee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far above the busy highway&lt;br&gt;
And the sleepy town&lt;br&gt;
Raised against the arch of heaven&lt;br&gt;
Looks she proudly down&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annapolis Valley STEAMspace</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/annapolis-valley-steamspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/annapolis-valley-steamspace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A place for Annapolis Valley Makers, inventors, artists, entrepreneurs, tinkerers and the like to meet, share ideas and work towards establishing the proposed Acadia University STEAMspace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CO3</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/co3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/co3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CO3 is a fresh bew co-working space for freelancers, entrepreneurs and independents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CO3 Is a concept created by &lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/andrew-button&#34;&gt;​Andrew Button&lt;/a&gt;
, a social entrepreneur based in Bridgewater, Nova Scotia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The mission is to create a space that further cultivates rural Nova Scotia&amp;rsquo;s freelance economy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the success of his own company Mashup Lab and other social ventures ​he&amp;rsquo;s discovered a lot of hidden talent in the Maritimes which he feels needs more room to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a member of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/the-hub-south-shore&#34;&gt;
    
        The HUB South Shore
    
&lt;/a&gt;
 himself, he knows the value of working with entrepreneurial spirited individuals and the impact it makes on self-confidence, motivation and forward thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Intellectual Property Office </title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/canadian-intellectual-property-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/canadian-intellectual-property-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Canadian Intellectual Property Office (CIPO), a Special Operating Agency (SOA) associated with Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada, is responsible for the administration and processing of the greater part of intellectual property in Canada. CIPO&amp;rsquo;s areas of activity include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patents cover new inventions (process, machine, manufacture, composition of matter), or any new and useful improvement of an existing invention;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A trademark is a word (or words), a design, or a combination of these, used to identify the goods or services of one person or organization and to distinguish these goods or services from those of others in the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copyright provide protection for artistic, dramatic, musical or literary works (including computer programs), and three other subject-matter known as: performance, sound recording and communication signal;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industrial designs are the visual features of shape, configuration, pattern or ornament (or any combination of these features), applied to a finished article of manufacture;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Integrated circuit topographies refer to the three-dimensional configurations of electronic circuits embodied in integrated circuit products or layout designs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canopy Creative</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/canopy-creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/canopy-creative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are a team of marketing consultants that work with small businesses to plan and strategize for marketing growth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colibri Software</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/colibri-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/colibri-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Colibri Software builds awesome software. We work with our clients to understand their needs and then produce a simple and effective solution to their problems. Our focus is on making a product easy to use, from websites to mobile apps, we like it when we hear “this is easy”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a special affinity for mapping projects and have send rugged phone apps as far as Nunavut to help collect data for the hunting community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Good Solutions</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/common-good-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/common-good-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Common Good Solutions (CGS) is a company focused on growing the social enterprise movement in Nova Scotia, Canada, and beyond. CGS operates a social enterprise incubator aimed at launching and supporting over 100 social businesses by 2019, and offers a full range of social enterprise consulting, mentoring and training services. Nova Scotia&amp;rsquo;s first Community Interest Company, CGS devotes 60% of all profits toward its social mission of growing the social enterprise sector in Nova Scotia. We support the Valley Startup Ecosystem through our full-time Social Enterprise Developer, dedicated specifically to the Valley and South Shore Region; working with entrepreneurs to start, grow and connect their enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Nova Scotia</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/digital-nova-scotia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/digital-nova-scotia/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Engaging both members and stakeholders in the region, Digital Nova Scotia provides advocacy, multi-sectoral industry intelligence, facilitates connections between industry and talent, and delivers high-level programming to ensure Nova Scotia’s $1.5 billion digital industry (which boasts an additional $1 billion in spin-offs) continues to flourish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-starts-here-it-stays-here-it-grows-here&#34;&gt;IT starts here. IT stays here. IT grows here.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the industry association for the fastest growing sector in the province with the highest number of ICT graduates per capita in Canada, Digital Nova Scotia encourages our tech talent and growing ecosystem of digital businesses to start here, stay here, and grow here! Nova Scotia has the “IT” factor: globally competitive talent, an ecosystem of support, advanced digital infrastructure, and a drive to push our economic boundaries. We are going for growth on a global scale!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enactus Acadia</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/enactus-acadia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/enactus-acadia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Enactus Acadia is a small chapter of a global organization that unites students with academic and business leaders. We implement various projects in the community that help improve the quality of life and standard of living for those in need. Enactus Acadia currently has multiple projects underway, which fit into categories such as eco-living, youth empowerment, financial literacy, and entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fusion Annapolis Valley</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/fusion-annapolis-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/fusion-annapolis-valley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fusion AV is a non-profit, community engagement organization that’s mission to engage with young professionals in the Annapolis Valley. We aim to give them opportunities to connect and build their personal and professional network to ensure the long term success of this great place we all call home.  Thus ENGAGE CONNECT SUCCEED&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>