<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entrepreneurship on Refresh Annapolis Valley</title>
    <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/topics/entrepreneurship/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entrepreneurship on Refresh Annapolis Valley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <atom:link href="https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/topics/entrepreneurship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Seed: Hacking Entrepreneurship in the Annapolis Valley</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/seed-hacking-entrepreneurship-in-the-annapolis-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 18:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/seed-hacking-entrepreneurship-in-the-annapolis-valley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seed&lt;/strong&gt; is a documentary that follows an international group of programmer entrepreneurs at Angelhack: one of the most competitive global hackathons and digital business ideation competitions. Three minutes to pitch. One shot to fund their proposals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seed&lt;/strong&gt; is also a gathering of our Annapolis Valley startup community.  The event will feature the diversity of associations, businesses, and individuals who comprise our digital tech startup community.  An assembly of our entrepreneurial family.  Come mingle and build your network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introductory keynote address by &lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/leanne-strathdee&#34;&gt;Leanne Strathdee&lt;/a&gt;
,
Manager of Innovation and Incubation for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre&#34;&gt;
    
        Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre
    
&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/4qyuHfRHLkc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Directed by Andrew Wonder and produced by Station Film and Something Different, &lt;strong&gt;Seed&lt;/strong&gt; is a documentary feature film which dives head first into the thrilling and daunting world of Silicon Valley. The film tells the story of the new American Dream, where innovators from around the world come to Silicon Valley with the hope of turning their ideas into billion dollar valuations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a riveting behind-the-scenes look at the preparation behind an investor pitch, Seed follows an Uber driver from New York, three local high school kids, and five college students from Nairobi as they compete in a high profile hackathon for the seed money they need to turn their dreams into reality. The rollercoaster ride of sleepless nights and tough-love coaching culminates in a final presentation before a full audience of tech executives and tastemakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Silicon Valley is a world where you only hear about big successes and IPOs, but never about the people who are fighting everyday to make their dreams a reality. I hope Seed can be an anthem for anyone who has gone down this path, successful or not, and show an honest look at what it takes to turn that app idea you had at dinner into a business that works,” Andrew Wonder says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew paints a vivid picture of the raw drive and passion that fuels each team. Their backstories come to life as the viewer watches each person experience both the lows from unexpected setbacks and highs when something finally goes right. Andrew captures these tensions, victories, and sacrifices through his organic observational approach; his keen eye draws out the humanity and spirit of each character’s unique story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film focuses on a hackathon competition hosted by AngelHack, a female-owned, female-majority company and the world’s largest and most diverse hacker community. “I’m grateful to AngelHack for the access they gave us and the teams for always being willing to share and let us in. It’s not easy to show how hard the path can be when all you want is for everyone else to see you as a success,” Andrew says of the partnership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.valleyren.ca/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/vren_logo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is supported by the amazing folks at the &lt;strong&gt;Valley Regional Enterprise Network&lt;/strong&gt; via their Collective Impact Project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Entrepreneurship: Turning Ideas into Action</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/creative-entrepreneurship-turning-ideas-into-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 12:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/creative-entrepreneurship-turning-ideas-into-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Problems and solutions.  In between are the numerous ideas that eventually lead to innovative solutions and new business opportunities.  Join the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre&#34;&gt;
    
        Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre
    
&lt;/a&gt;
 for a talk all about ideas.  Where do they come from?  How do we nurture them?  How can we turn them into problem solving new business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build your mad ideation skills at this workshop, then take them to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.startituplaunchbox.com/&#34;&gt;Start It Up&lt;/a&gt;: our business ideation competition with $10K in prizes on the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pizza + workshop + building&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring your own laptop. A small number of laptops will be available to borrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First time Hoisters need to get a parent or guardian to &lt;a href=&#34;https://form.jotform.ca/71164477795267&#34;&gt;fill out the consent form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Founders Meetup: Lets Start a Business</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/founders-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 13:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/founders-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this Hoist meetup, we will be doing something a little different.  We are looking for a few budding teen entrepreneurs to start a business.  This is the pitch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Services supporting the business startup space in Rural Nova Scotia are diverse and not well represented as a whole.  Our business aims to unify the Western Nova business startup ecosystem by building a coherent communication platform.  By doing so, we will encourage entrepreneurship within our community.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are looking for teens with a range of interests to flesh out this initiative:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Designer&lt;/strong&gt;: Logos, web design, brand aesthetics. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software development&lt;/strong&gt;: HTML, JavaScript, server management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business development&lt;/strong&gt;: Idea generation, shape features, market fit, competitive landscape, research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing and sales&lt;/strong&gt;: Evangelism, blogging, advertising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content management&lt;/strong&gt;: Master wordsmith, create original content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accounting&lt;/strong&gt;: Budgeting, account receivables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t have mad skillz to share, no problem.  You just need passion.  We will learn as we go, bringing in subject matter experts to beef up our skill set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring your own laptop. A small number of laptops will be available to borrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First time Hoisters need to get a parent or guardian to &lt;a href=&#34;https://form.jotform.ca/71164477795267&#34;&gt;fill out the consent form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoist Annapolis Valley</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/hoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/hoist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hoist Annapolis Valley is a tech club for teens interested in coding, design and entrepreneurship. If you’re age 12 to 19 and have an interest in startups or coding, then come check it out! Everyone is welcome, and it’s free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet up with Hoist members once per month at Acadia University&amp;rsquo;s Rural Innovation Centre &amp;ndash; like attending an tech + entrepreneurship class at university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-hoist-way&#34;&gt;The Hoist Way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lunch!&lt;/strong&gt; Have some pizza with your new friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn!&lt;/strong&gt; The first half-hour will be a lesson from a pro on the topic of the day – coding…design or business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hack!&lt;/strong&gt; Build or design something, apply what you just learned…it’s a mini hackathon. Work in a group or on your own to create the next big product or service!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discuss!&lt;/strong&gt; Reflect and discuss the day…what did you find challenging or exciting? Chill out and talk to your new pals about what you created!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our &lt;strong&gt;mailing list&lt;/strong&gt; (see below) to stay up-to-date about our upcoming meetups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-thanks&#34;&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big tip of the hat to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre&#34;&gt;
    
        Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre
    
&lt;/a&gt;
 for hosting our meetup, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/launchbox&#34;&gt;
    
        launchbox
    
&lt;/a&gt;
 for helping out in numerous ways.  And &lt;a href=&#34;http://hoisthalifax.com/&#34;&gt;Hoist Halifax&lt;/a&gt; for paving the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Meetups</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/meetups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/meetups/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Our monthly Refresh meetup is where the Annapolis Valley community of designers, developers and innovators come hang out.  Those interested in the creative, technical, and professional culture of digital technology endeavours in the Annapolis Valley meet and talk about all things design, technology, and entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refresh meets the second Tuesday evening of each month in the Wolfville area. These are casual affairs with short, member-interest talks followed by an opportunity to mingle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All are welcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our &lt;strong&gt;mailing list&lt;/strong&gt; (see below) to stay up-to-date about our upcoming meetups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-thanks&#34;&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big tip of the hat to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre&#34;&gt;
    
        Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre
    
&lt;/a&gt;
 for hosting our meetup and &lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/innovacorp&#34;&gt;
    
        innovacorp
    
&lt;/a&gt;
 for keeping the dream alive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;AEC has been developing and delivering workshops for business professionals, entrepreneurs, and not-for-profits for over 25 years. AEC continues to innovate and develop new and relevant programs for today’s business professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rural-innovation-centre&#34;&gt;Rural Innovation Centre&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rural Innovation Centre (RIC) supports entrepreneurs and businesses in the Annapolis Valley and on the South Shore by providing training, advisory and consulting services to small businesses, government and not-for-profit organizations. The Rural Innovation Centre is an incubator for start up companies to access working space and support, networking events, mentors and connect to Acadia faculty and facilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;launchbox&#34;&gt;Launchbox&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/launchbox&#34;&gt;
    
        Launchbox
    
&lt;/a&gt;
 is the centre for student entrepreneurs, located on the 4th floor of Patterson Hall at Acadia University. We support students in their entrepreneurial pursuits by providing free programming, networking, access to mentors, and other entrepreneurs, working space and competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launchbox</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/launchbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/launchbox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launchbox is the centre for student entrepreneurs, located on the 4th floor of Patterson Hall at Acadia University. We support students in their entrepreneurial pursuits by providing free programming, networking, access to mentors, and other entrepreneurs, working space and competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>