<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entrepreneurship on Refresh Annapolis Valley</title>
    <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/topics/entrepreneurship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entrepreneurship on Refresh Annapolis Valley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/topics/entrepreneurship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Our Digital Nation: Digital Nova Scotia 2019</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/state-of-our-digital-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/state-of-our-digital-nation/</guid>
      <description>Nova Scotia&amp;rsquo;s digital economy is currently valued at $2.5 billion. Tyler Farmer, Project Manager at Digital Nova Scotia, will present a state of our digital nation, reflecting on trends and opportunities, both urban and rural. Join us for our last Refresh meetup for the 2018-2019 year for discussion and drinks care of our host, Annapolis Cider Company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovating on The Internet</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/innovating-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 19:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/innovating-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>Have the next (big or small) idea, no budget, or development skills? No problem &amp;ndash; you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t start with building anyway.
In this hands on workshop we will explore pre-product design tools that anyone can pick up to express their app idea. With these tools you will walk away with a means to engage your user base to test concepts, gather feedback quickly, very inexpensively, and early on in the product cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Succeeding at Failing</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/succeeding-at-failing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 19:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/succeeding-at-failing/</guid>
      <description>Behind every entrepreneurial success lie the stories of numerous failures. As a mindset, entrepreneurship is characterized by risk-taking, experimentation, and continually challenging oneself to produce meaningful results. It is also about learning from failure, and, where possible, finding new ways to tackle problems that eventually lead to success.
Join Katelyn Bourgoin , a 3X founder/business owner turned growth strategist, for a discussion about how to think about entrepreneurship. Come mingle with a wide cross section of Annapolis Valley entrepreneurs for drinks, networking, and old fashioned discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katelyn Bourgoin</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/katelyn-bourgoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/katelyn-bourgoin/</guid>
      <description>Katelyn Bourgoin is a 3X founder/business owner turned growth strategist. She helps frustrated marketers and business owners to figure out why customers aren’t buying and how they can fix it.
When companies know who their best customers are and what they really want, it becomes much easier to create awesome products and sell more of them. The result? Happier customers and more money in the bank.
Katelyn’s past clients include startups, small businesses, and Fortune 500s like Target and Holiday Inn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seed: Hacking Entrepreneurship in the Annapolis Valley</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/seed-hacking-entrepreneurship-in-the-annapolis-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 18:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/seed-hacking-entrepreneurship-in-the-annapolis-valley/</guid>
      <description>Seed is a documentary that follows an international group of programmer entrepreneurs at AngelHack: one of the most competitive global hackathons and digital business ideation competitions. Three minutes to pitch. One shot to fund their proposals.
Seed is also a gathering of our Annapolis Valley startup community. The event will feature the diversity of associations, businesses, and individuals who comprise our digital tech startup community. An assembly of our entrepreneurial family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Entrepreneurship: Turning Ideas into Action</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/creative-entrepreneurship-turning-ideas-into-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 12:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/creative-entrepreneurship-turning-ideas-into-action/</guid>
      <description>Problems and solutions. In between are the numerous ideas that eventually lead to innovative solutions and new business opportunities. Join the Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre  for a talk all about ideas. Where do they come from? How do we nurture them? How can we turn them into problem solving new business?
Build your mad ideation skills at this workshop, then take them to Start It Up: our business ideation competition with $10K in prizes on the line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Founders Meetup: Lets Start a Business</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/founders-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 13:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/founders-meetup/</guid>
      <description>For this Hoist meetup, we will be doing something a little different. We are looking for a few budding teen entrepreneurs to start a business. This is the pitch:
Services supporting the business startup space in Rural Nova Scotia are diverse and not well represented as a whole. Our business aims to unify the Western Nova business startup ecosystem by building a coherent communication platform. By doing so, we will encourage entrepreneurship within our community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoist Annapolis Valley</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/hoist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/hoist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hoist Annapolis Valley is a tech club for teens interested in coding, design and entrepreneurship. If you’re age 12 to 19 and have an interest in startups or coding, then come check it out! Everyone is welcome, and it’s free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet up with Hoist members once per month at Acadia University&amp;rsquo;s Rural Innovation Centre &amp;ndash; like attending an tech + entrepreneurship class at university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labs</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/labs/</guid>
      <description>The Refresh Annapolis Valley Labs is a playground where adventurous builders come to create. Labs initiatives are community driven digital technology projects that tend to be entrepreneurial in nature. In the lab, Refreshers work on building and applying their skills all while pursuing the objectives of their projects.
Refresh Annapolis Valley Labs is hosted at the Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre Rural Innovation Centre. We meet on Saturdays from 12:30 to 3:30 starting January 26.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Meetups</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/meetups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/meetups/</guid>
      <description>Our monthly Refresh meetup is where the Annapolis Valley community of designers, developers and innovators come hang out. Those interested in the creative, technical, and professional culture of digital technology endeavours in the Annapolis Valley meet and talk about all things design, technology, and entrepreneurship.
Refresh meets the second Tuesday evening of each month in the Wolfville area. These are casual affairs with short, member-interest talks followed by an opportunity to mingle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AVCC Young Business Leaders</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/young-business-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/young-business-leaders/</guid>
      <description>Annapolis Valley Chamber of Commerce Young Business Leaders is a new committee that is exploring ways to connect to established business leaders for advice and mentorship. The AVCC Young Business Leaders Committee will recognize, encourage and engage future business leaders. The Young Business Leaders meet the last Tuesday of each month at noon at Gates Insurance, New Minas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/acadia-entrepreneurship-centre/</guid>
      <description>AEC has been developing and delivering workshops for business professionals, entrepreneurs, and not-for-profits for over 25 years. AEC continues to innovate and develop new and relevant programs for today’s business professional.
Rural Innovation Centre The Rural Innovation Centre (RIC) supports entrepreneurs and businesses in the Annapolis Valley and on the South Shore by providing training, advisory and consulting services to small businesses, government and not-for-profit organizations. The Rural Innovation Centre is an incubator for start up companies to access working space and support, networking events, mentors and connect to Acadia faculty and facilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annapolis Valley Chamber of Commerce</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/annapolis-valley-chamber-of-commerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/annapolis-valley-chamber-of-commerce/</guid>
      <description>Annapolis Valley Chamber of Commerce is a strong united voice for business and works to ensure that business thrives in the Annapolis Valley.
AVCC is a not-for-profit organization that provides member businesses with access to a variety of services such as group insurance, professional development and networking opportunities. AVCC celebrates and promotes the accomplishments of business people and their contribution to the valley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launchbox</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/launchbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/organization/launchbox/</guid>
      <description>Launchbox is the centre for student entrepreneurs, located on the 4th floor of Patterson Hall at Acadia University. We support students in their entrepreneurial pursuits by providing free programming, networking, access to mentors, and other entrepreneurs, working space and competitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noah Tomkins</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/noah-tomkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/noah-tomkins/</guid>
      <description>Originally from Dartmouth, Nova Scotia, Noah Tompkins is a fourth-year Entrepreneurship &amp;amp; Innovation major at Acadia University. His passion for sustainability and social enterprise has lead Noah to working as the Marketing Coordinator for Just Us! Coffee Roasters, becoming a project manager and presenter for Enacts Acadia, and the President of Fair Trade Acadia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sara Baxter</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/sara-baxter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/sara-baxter/</guid>
      <description>A fourth year Accounting major, Sara Baxter from Moncton, New Brunswick, exercises her entrepreneurial skillset through Acadia Entrepreneurship Centre as the Community Entrepreneurship Developer. Her desire to create change and have a positive impact on society has led her to become a Project Co-Manager for Enacts Acadia&amp;rsquo;s Project Regenerate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tyler Farmer</title>
      <link>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/tyler-farmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/person/tyler-farmer/</guid>
      <description>For the last year and a half, Tyler has lead Digital Nova Scotia’s projects and skill development programs across Nova Scotia. Through this role, Tyler has had the opportunity to connect with a wide variety of ICT &amp;amp; digital tech companies, professional service providers, community leaders, and government agencies which has enabled him to build an effective grassroots network with a birds-eye perspective of the economic challenges facing the province. Prior to diving into the rewarding work of economic development through Nova Scotia’s IT association, Tyler coordinated inspection, expediting, and project management services for many of Canada’s leading oil and gas companies in Alberta.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>